halfords.com 2018-05-23

# Help & Advice | Customer Services | Policies & Regulations

  * App Terms and Conditions
  * Website Terms and Conditions
  * Terms of Use
  * App Privacy Policy
  * Privacy Policy
  * Olapic Terms and Conditions
  * Cookie Policy
  * Chemical Regulations
  * Terms for free in-store WiFi

## App Terms and Conditions

### App Terms and Conditions

By downloading or using the Halfords App (the "App") you agree to these terms and conditions. You should read them carefully before using the App. You're not allowed to copy or modify the App, any part of the app, or our trademarks in any way. You're not allowed to attempt to extract the source code of the App, and you also shouldn't try to translate the app into other languages, or make derivative versions. The App itself, and all the trade marks, copyright, database rights and other intellectual property rights related to it, belong to Halfords. 

At the top of this page you'll be able to find links to our Privacy Policy and Terms of Use of both the website and the App. The App stores and processes personal data that you've provided us with, and this may be shared with third parties so that the App can operate as you need it to. Full details are set out in our Privacy Policy. It's your responsibility to keep your device and access to the App secure. 

We reserve the right to make changes to the App or to charge for its services, at any time and for any reason. 

We cannot take responsibility for the App not working at full functionality or for any way in which you use the App including for any charges you incur by using the App (for example, from your mobile provider). In using the App, you're accepting responsibility for any such charges. If you're not the bill payer for the device on which you're using the App, by using the App you agree that you've received permission from the bill payer for using the App. 

Occasionally we'll need to update the App. You'll need to download the updates if you want to keep using the App. We do not promise that it will always update the App so that it's relevant to you and/or works with your device. We may terminate use of the App at any time without giving notice of termination to you. Unless we tell you otherwise, upon any termination, (a) the rights and licenses granted to you in these terms will end; (b) you must stop using the App, and (if needed) delete it from your device.

Back to top

## Website Terms and Conditions

These are the Terms and Conditions of Sale for Halfords.com to which all online purchases are subject.

### 1\. Definitions

1.1. In these Conditions, the following definitions shall apply: 

**Approved Partner:** a third party seller who sells Goods to Customers using the Marketplace.   
**Business Days:** a day (other than a Saturday, Sunday or public holiday) when banks in London are open for business.   
**Conditions:** the terms and conditions set out in this document as amended from time to time in accordance with clause 14.   
**Contract:** the contract between us and the Customer for the sale and purchase of the Goods in accordance with these Conditions.   
**Customer, you, your:** the person who purchases the Goods from us.   
**Event Outside Our Control:** has the meaning given in clause 13.   
**Goods:** the goods (or any part of them) set out in the Order.   
**Halfords:** Halfords Limited (registered in England and Wales with company number 00103161 with registered office address at Icknield Street Drive, Washford West, Redditch, Worcestershire B98 0DE.   
**Halfords Goods:** Goods purchased on the Website from Halfords and not an Approved Partner.   
**Marketplace:** the marketplace accessed via the Website through which Halfords facilitates transactions between Approved Partners and Customers.   
**Order:** the Customer's order for the Goods submitted by the Customer online via the Website.  
**Website:** means the website accessible at Halfords.com including the Marketplace.   
**We, us, our:** Halfords or the Approved Partner as applicable to the Order.

1.2. In these Conditions, the following rules apply:

1.2.1. A person includes a natural person, corporate or unincorporated body (whether or not having separate legal personality).   
1.2.2. A reference to a party includes its personal representatives, successors or permitted assigns.   
1.2.3. Any phrase introduced by the terms including, include, in particular or any similar expression shall be construed as illustrative and shall not limit the sense of the words preceding those terms.   
1.2.4. A reference to writing or written includes e-mails.

### 2\. The Contract

2.1. The Order you place via the Website constitutes an offer to purchase the Goods in accordance with these Conditions. You are responsible for ensuring that the terms of the Order are correct. Please read and check your Order before placing. You may only purchase Goods from us if you meet any legal age requirement necessary for the acquisition of the same.

2.2. The Order shall only be deemed accepted by us when you have paid for the Goods, monies received by us and the Goods have been dispatched. Any email, order confirmation or other electronic acknowledgement by us of receipt of an Order does not constitute legal acceptance by us of your Order. We will confirm our acceptance to you by sending you an email confirming that the Goods have been dispatched (' **Dispatch Confirmation** '). The Contract between us is formed when we send you the Dispatch Confirmation.

2.3. All Orders placed via the Website are subject to stock availability and to the validation checks described in Clause 5 below. In the unlikely event that you are able to place an Order for an item that is not available from stock, we will contact you as soon as possible. Depending on the time period for stock to arrive you may be given the option to wait for your items or your Order will be cancelled. In these circumstances, upon cancellation, you will be refunded in full.

2.4. We only accept Orders originating from and for delivery to UK addresses.

2.5. The only language in which the Contract can be concluded is English. 

2.6. We will retain details of your Order in our database and these details can be made available to you on request. Please contact our _Customer Service team_.

2.7. Where the Customer has been directed to the Website as a result of a third party site, these sites are independent from us and we are not responsible or liable for such sites. Customers should consult the terms and conditions of the site in question for more information.

2.8. For information on how to shop at Halfords.com, visit _our step-by-step guide_.

2.9. Where you place an Order from an Approved Partner via the Marketplace:   
2.9.1 the Contract is made between you and the Approved Partner and these Conditions apply to such Contracts.   
2.9.2 Halfords act as the Approved Partner's agent for payment and you authorise Halfords to process payment on their behalf.   
2.9.3 Other than as set out in clause 2.9.2 above, Halfords has no responsibility to you in respect of Contracts made with Approved Partners and all references in these Conditions to 'we' 'us' or 'our' shall be deemed to refer to the Approved Partner in that context.   
2.9.4 In the first instance the Customer must attempt to resolve any dispute directly with the Approved Partner.   
2.9.5 Approved Partners shall not invoice Customers directly, and Customers must not accept or pay Approved Partners invoices.

### 3\. Product Information

3.1. Goods are described on the Website.

3.2. We reserve the right to amend the product description if required.

3.3. Images of the Goods on the Website are for illustrative purposes only. Representations of colour online are as accurate as our photographic and electronic processes will allow. Please note that colour online can also be affected by the calibrations of different output devices.

3.4. All weights and sizes are supplied as a guide only and are approximate.

3.5. Guided Sales, Buyers Guides and all other advice articles have been produced by Halfords to help you in your purchasing decisions and to give guidance. These articles are provided for general information, but if you are in any doubt, you should seek help from an appropriate professional. We accept no liability for any loss, damage or injury arising as a result of the advice contained on our Website.

3.6. In the event that there are any errors regarding price or description, we reserve the right to correct that price or description and notify you accordingly. In these circumstances, it will be deemed that a contract has not been entered into and you will not be bound to continue with your purchase. We will cancel your Order and your credit/debit card or your Paypal account will be refunded in full. The repayment of such monies paid to us will be the extent of our liability to you in the event of these errors.

### 4\. Price Information

4.1. The price of the Goods is the price set out on the Website at the time you submit your Order. All prices are shown in Pounds Sterling.

4.2. The price of the Goods does not include delivery charges which will be as advised during the check-out process, before you confirm your Order.

4.3. The price of the Goods is inclusive of VAT (where applicable) at the current rate chargeable in the UK. If the rate of VAT changes between the date of Order and the date of delivery, we will adjust the VAT you pay unless you have already paid for the Goods in full before the change in VAT. Halfords VAT number is 797 0776 69. VAT numbers of Approved Partners are listed on their respective 'About Us' pages in the Marketplace.

4.4. Where the 'In-store Price' is listed, this refers to the current price in Halfords stores.

4.5. The prices shown are only applicable to purchases made via the Website. On occasions, the prices payable and promotions offered online may differ from those prices and promotions offered at the same time in Halfords stores. Where the online price is lower than our store price we will match in store. This is in line with the Halfords Price Match Promise which is subject to Terms and Conditions. For more information regarding this service and to help us process your Price Match enquiry please see our _Shopping at Halfords_ page.

4.6. Special Offers and promotions advertised in the press or other media may be excluded from the Website unless specifically advertised as available online. All offers are subject to availability and while stocks last. This includes all offers advertised via official Halfords social media channels.

4.7. Offers cannot be used in conjunction with one another. Where more than one offer is available on the same product only one discount will apply. The offer giving the greatest saving will be applied in the basket. Equally, voucher code offers cannot be used in conjunction with any other promotional offer.

### 5\. Payment Information

5.1. Halfords.com accepts payment by most major credit or debit cards registered at UK addresses, or by Paypal registered to UK addresses. We regret that we are unable to accept payment online by cheque, cash, Halfords Gift Vouchers, Halfords Gift Cards, High Street Vouchers, Purchase Orders or any other form of payment. For more information about payment methods, please _click here_.

5.2. Please ensure that the expiry date of your credit or debit card is after the anticipated despatch date of your Order. Payment will be debited from your account just before the despatch of your Goods, and if your payment card has expired, we will be unable to take payment and fulfil your Order.

5.3. When an Order is placed a pre-authorisation will be made against your account. Payment is not taken at this time. Halfords will endeavour to process any payments at the time of dispatch. On the rare occasion that this process is not successful, we will re-process accordingly. We will not inform you if this delay occurs. Halfords are not liable for any bank charges that may be incurred by the Customer if sufficient funds are not available at the time when payment is taken.

5.4. All credit and debit card holders are subject to validation checks and authorisation by the card issuer. If the issuer of your payment card refuses to authorise payment to us, we will not be liable for any delay or non-delivery. 

5.5. In addition, to prevent fraudulent use of credit and debit cards, Halfords will validate the names, addresses and other information supplied during the Order process against commercially available records (e.g. Electoral Roll data, Credit Reference Services). A third party may also be instructed to complete these checks. By ordering from the Website you consent to such checks being made. We may need to contact you by letter, telephone or email to verify details before we are able to process and dispatch your Order or we may be unable to accept your Order. Any information given may be disclosed to a registered Credit Reference Agency which may keep a record of the information. All information provided will be treated in accordance with the Data Protection Act 1998.

5.6. Where your Contract is with an Approved Partner, you consent to Halfords sharing your personal data with the Approved Partner for the purposes of fulfilling your Order including sending dispatch notifications and dispatching the Goods. 

### 6\. Delivery of Goods

6.1. We can only deliver to addresses within the United Kingdom. Unfortunately, we are unable to deliver to non-UK destinations, including the Republic of Ireland, the Channel Islands and BFPO addresses at this time. Please _contact us_ if you require further details.

6.2. For deliveries to non-mainland UK addresses and certain remote locations e.g. Scottish Isles, Isle of Man, Isle of Wight, Northern Ireland and the Scottish Highlands, there may be an additional surcharge imposed by our couriers and a slightly longer delivery lead-time.

6.3. The delivery charge for each item is listed on the product detail page. When you add products to your shopping basket and have chosen the delivery option the appropriate charge will be added automatically. All delivery charges will be shown clearly throughout the checkout process. For more information about delivery charges and lead times, _click here_.

6.4. We may deliver the Goods by instalments, which shall be invoiced and paid for separately. Each instalment shall constitute a separate Contract. Any delay in delivery or defect in an instalment shall not entitle the Customer to cancel any other instalment.

6.5 Any dates quoted for delivery are approximate only and we cannot be held liable for any costs incurred if delivery is delayed.

6.5.1. Please be aware that Royal Mail First Class postal service can take up to 7 days. This is under the terms of Royal Mail and is out of our control.   
6.5.2. 3rd Party couriers can deliver direct delivery orders between the hours of 7am and 9pm. 

6.6. Delivery of an Order shall be completed when we deliver the Goods to the delivery address given in the Order.

6.7. The Goods will be your responsibility from the time of delivery.

6.8. Where the courier is unable to deliver the Goods, they will either attempt to deliver to a neighbour, attempt to redeliver the following day, leave a card for you to rearrange a suitable time for redelivery or leave the parcel at your local Post Office for you to collect.

6.9. We shall have no liability for any delay in delivery of the Goods, or failure to deliver the Goods, where the delay or failure is caused either by an Event Outside Our Control or the Customer's failure to provide us with adequate delivery instructions or any other instructions that are relevant to the supply of the Goods.

6.10 If we miss our estimated delivery deadline for the Goods or, in the absence of any estimate being given the date 30 days after the Dispatch Confirmation, you may cancel your Order straight away if any of the following apply:   
(a) we have refused to deliver the Goods;   
(b) delivery within the delivery deadline was essential (taking into account all the relevant circumstances); or   
(c) you told us before we accepted your Order that delivery within the delivery deadline was essential.

6.11 If you do not wish to cancel your Order straight away, or do not have the right to do so under clause 6.10 you can give us a new deadline for delivery which must be reasonable, and you can cancel your Order if we do not meet the new deadline. 

6.12 If you do choose to cancel your Order for late delivery under clause 6.10 or clause 6.7, you can do so for just some of the Goods or all of them, unless splitting them up would significantly reduce their value. If the Goods have been delivered to you, you will have to return them to us or allow us to collect them, and we will pay the costs of this. After you cancel your Order we will refund any sums you have paid to us for the cancelled Goods and their delivery.

### 7 . Refunds and Returns

7.1 Refunds and returns of Goods purchased from an Approved Partner must be arranged directly with that Approved Partner, in accordance with the process set out on its 'About Us' page in the Marketplace. The rest of this clause 7 relates to refunds and returns of Halfords Goods only. Advice about your legal right to cancel the Contract is available from your local Citizens' Advice Bureau or Trading Standards office. 

7.2 If you are a consumer, you have a legal right to cancel a Contract under the Consumer Contracts (Information, Cancellation and Additional Charges) Regulations 2013 within 14 days of receipt of Goods however for Halfords Goods, Halfords have extended that right to 28 days from receipt of the Goods (please see clause 7.4 below for an explanation of the period during which you can cancel a Contract). This means that during the relevant period if you change your mind or decide for any other reason that you do not want to receive or keep the Goods, you can notify us of your decision to cancel the Contract and receive a refund. Alternatively, you are entitled to request an exchange within the same period of time and the provisions below also apply to exchanges.

7.3 However, this cancellation right does not apply in the case of the following which may only be returned if they are faulty:  
(a) personalised and made-to-order products;   
(b) sealed satellite navigation equipment, sealed memory cards, sealed audio or sealed video recordings or sealed computer software which have been unsealed after you receive them.   
(c) any Goods which become mixed inseparably with other items after their delivery.

7.4 Your legal right to cancel a Contract starts from the date of the Dispatch Confirmation (the date on which we e-mail you to confirm our acceptance of your order), which is when the Contract between us is formed. Your deadline for cancelling the Contract then depends on what you have ordered and how it is delivered, as set out in the table below:

Your Contract | End of the cancellation period  
---|---  
Your Contract is for Goods which are not delivered in instalments on separate days. | The end date is the end of 28 days after the day on which you receive the Goods. Example: if we provide you with a Dispatch Confirmation on 1 January and you receive the Goods on 10 January you may cancel at any time between 1 January and the end of the day on 7 February.  
Your Contract is for Goods which are delivered in instalments on separate days. | The end date is 28 days after the day on which you receive the last instalment of the Goods or the last of the separate Goods ordered.  
Example: if we provide you with a Dispatch Confirmation on 1 January and you receive the first instalment of your Goods on 10 January and the last instalment or last separate item of your Goods on 15 January you may cancel in respect of all instalments and any or all of the separate Goods at any time between 1 January and the end of the day on 12 February.  
Your Contract is for the regular delivery of Goods over a set period. | The end date is 28 days after the day on which you receive the first delivery of the Goods.  
Example: if we provide you with a Dispatch Confirmation on 1 January in respect of Goods to be delivered at regular intervals over a year and you receive the first delivery of your Goods on 10 January, you may cancel at any time between 1 January and the end of the day on 7 February. 7 February is the last day of the cancellation period in respect of all Goods to arrive during the year.  
  
7.5 To cancel a Contract with Halfords, you need to let us know that you have decided to cancel. If you wish to exercise this right, please contact the Halfords Customer Services Team, by phone, email or letter sent by post or using the online form on our Website. If you use the online form we will e-mail you to confirm we have received your cancellation. If you are e-mailing us or writing to us please include details of your Order to help us to identify it. If you send us your cancellation notice by e-mail or by post, then your cancellation is effective from the date you send us the e-mail or post the letter to us. For example, you will have given us notice in time as long as you get your letter into the last post on the last day of the cancellation period or e-mail us before midnight on that day.

7.6 If you cancel your Contract with Halfords, Halfords will:  
(a) refund you the price you paid for the Goods. However, please note we are permitted by law to reduce your refund to reflect any reduction in the value of the goods, if this has been caused by your handling them in a way which would not be permitted in a shop. If we refund you the price paid before we are able to inspect the goods and later discover you have handled them in an unacceptable way, you must pay us an appropriate amount.   
(b) refund any delivery costs you have paid.   
(c) make any refunds due to you as soon as possible and in any event within the deadlines indicated below:  
(i) if you have received the Goods and we have not offered to collect it from you: 14 days after the day on which we receive the Goods back from you or, if earlier, the day on which you provide us with evidence that you have sent the Goods back to us. For information about how to return Goods to us, see clause 9.8.   
(ii) if you have not received the Goods or you have received it and we have offered to collect it from you: 14 days after you inform us of your decision to cancel the Contract. 

7.7 If you have returned the Goods to us under this clause 7 because they are faulty or mis-described, we will refund the price of the Goods in full, together with any applicable delivery charges. 

7.8 We will refund you on the credit card or debit card used by you to pay. If you used vouchers to pay for the Goods we may refund you in vouchers.

7.9 If Goods have been delivered to you before you decide to cancel your Contract:   
(a) then you must return it to us without undue delay and in any event not later than 14 days after the day on which you let us know that you wish to cancel the Contract. You can either send it back (and we recommend using a trackable service and obtaining proof of postage), return it to us in-store or hand it to our authorised carrier. For information on how to return an item please click here. You must take reasonable care to ensure that the Goods are not damaged in transit; this includes ensuring that they are securely packaged. Halfords cannot be responsible for lost or damaged returns.   
(b) unless the Goods are faulty or not as described (in this case, see clause 7.7, you will be responsible for the cost of returning the Goods to us. If the Goods cannot be returned by post, we may offer to collect the Goods from you in which case we will charge you the direct cost to us of collection which will be £7.

7.10 Because you are a consumer, we are under a legal duty to supply Goods that are in conformity with this Contract. As a consumer, you have legal rights in relation to Goods that are faulty or not as described. These legal rights are not affected by your right of return and refund in this clause 7 or anything else in these Conditions. Advice about your legal rights is available from your local Citizens' Advice Bureau or Trading Standards office. For our returns policy, please _click here_.

7.11. Due to the speed of our ordering process, Halfords may not be able to cancel your order before despatch. If you exercise your right to cancel prior to you receiving the Goods, Halfords will attempt to stop the goods in transit, however if this is not possible and the Goods are delivered, you will be able to return your Goods in line with your rights outlined above.

### 8\. After-sales Service and Guarantees

8.1. Where applicable, details of manufacturers' guarantees or service arrangements will be provided with the Goods. In respect of Halfords Goods (only), your local Halfords superstore will initially deal with after sales service and warranty/ guarantee claims. In relation to Goods purchased from Approved Partners, you should contact them directly to discuss service, warranty and guarantee claims. A manufacturer's guarantee is in addition to, and does not affect, your legal rights in relation to Goods that are faulty or not as described.

8.2. All warranties are non-transferable and only apply for the original Customer. Please note that, if you buy Goods with a Halfords warranty, we are guaranteeing that those Goods will work during the warranty period. If you replace the Goods during the warranty period, the warranty does not start again. You will only benefit from the remaining period of the original warranty. This does not affect your statutory rights if the Goods are faulty or not as described.

8.3. We are under a legal duty to supply goods that are in conformity with the contract.

8.4. If you have any further queries relating to Halfords Goods once you have spoken to your local store, please don't hesitate to _contact us_.

8.5.For further information on guarantees, please _click here_.

### 9\. Complaints and Queries

9.1.If you are not happy with any aspect of our online service, discover a fault with our Website, or if you have any queries or comments relating to an order placed online, please _contact us_ and we will do everything we can to help you.

9.2. If we have exhausted our internal complaints handling procedure and we inform you in writing that we cannot settle your complaint, you have the option of referring your complaint to an Alternative Dispute Resolution ("ADR") provider to deal with the same. We are not obliged to use a specific ADR provider or procedure, however, a list of certified providers can be found at [_www.tradingstandards.uk/advice/ADRApprovedBodies.cfm_](http://www.tradingstandards.uk/advice/ADRApprovedBodies.cfm). Alternatively, you can refer the complaint to the EU Commission's Online Dispute Resolution (ODR) Platform at wwww.odreurope.com. Please note that we are not obliged to participate in ADR.

9.3. Your access to Halfords.com may occasionally be restricted to allow for the introduction of new products or features, site development, maintenance or repairs. We will attempt to restore the service as soon as we reasonably can.

### 10\. Safe Shopping Guarantee

10.1. We have used every effort to ensure that shopping on the internet with Halfords is as safe as purchasing by card in a regular Halfords store. Our secure server software encrypts all of your personal information sent over the Internet. In processing your Order, your information may have to be sent over the internet more than once. At no point is your Order information sent in this way without encryption.

10.2. Although Halfords endeavour to take all reasonable steps to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee the complete security of any data you disclose online. You accept the inherent security risks of providing personal information and dealing online over the Internet and Halfords cannot be held responsible for any breach of security unless it is due to our negligence. Please read our _Privacy Policy_ for more details.

### 11\. Comodo Authentic Site

This Website has been issued with a Secure Server Digital Certificate by the online Certificate Authority Comodo and has been authorised to display the Comodo Authentic Site seal. The Comodo Digital ID is an electronic licence credential for online business. It confirms that the Website is a legitimate website and establishes an encrypted communication channel protecting all sensitive and personal information you send over the Internet while you are using this website.

The Halfords Website is operated by:   
Halfords Limited   
Icknield Street Drive   
Washford West   
Redditch   
Worcestershire   
B98 0DE

Registered in England and Wales. Company Number 103161.

### 12\. Liability

12.1 If we fail to comply with these Conditions, we are responsible for loss or damage you suffer that is a foreseeable result of our breach of these Conditions or our negligence, but we are not responsible for any loss or damage that is not foreseeable. Loss or damage is foreseeable if it is an obvious consequence of our breach or if it was contemplated by you and us at the time we entered into this Contract.

12.2 We only supply the Goods for domestic and private use. You agree not to use the Goods for any commercial, business or resale purposes, and we have no liability to you for any loss of profit, loss of business, business interruption, or loss of business opportunity.

12.3 We do not in any way exclude or limit our liability for:   
(a) death or personal injury caused by our negligence;   
(b) fraud or fraudulent misrepresentation;   
(c) any breach of the terms implied by section 12 of the Sale of Goods Act 1979 (title and quiet possession);   
(d) any breach of the terms implied by section 13 to 15 of the Sale of Goods Act 1979 (description, satisfactory quality, fitness for purpose and samples); and   
(e) defective products under the Consumer Protection Act 1987.

### 13\. Events Outside Our Control

We will not be liable or responsible for any failure to perform, or delay in performance of, any of our obligations under a Contract that is caused by an Event Outside Our Control. An Event Outside Our Control means any act or event beyond our reasonable control, including without limitation strikes, lock-outs or other industrial action by third parties, civil commotion, riot, invasion, terrorist attack or threat of terrorist attack, war (whether declared or not) or threat or preparation for war, fire, explosion, storm, flood, earthquake, subsidence, epidemic or other natural disaster, or failure of public or private telecommunications networks or impossibility of the use of railways, shipping, aircraft, motor transport or other means of public or private transport.

### 14\. Variation

Halfords amends these Conditions from time to time. Each time you order Goods from us, the Conditions in force at the time of your Order apply to the Contract between you and us.

### 15\. Communications between us

15.1. Any notice or other communication given to the Customer under or in connection with the Contract shall be in writing (including email), addressed to the Customer at the address that the Customer has specified to us in writing in accordance with this clause, and shall be delivered personally, sent by pre-paid first class post, recorded delivery, commercial courier, fax or e-mail.

15.2. A notice or other communication shall be deemed to have been received: if delivered personally, when left at the address referred to in clause 15.1; if sent by pre-paid first class post or recorded delivery, at 9.00 am on the second Business Day after posting; if delivered by commercial courier, on the date and at the time that the courier's delivery receipt is signed; or, if sent by fax or e-mail, one Business Day after transmission.

15.3. The provisions of this clause shall not apply to the service of any proceedings or other documents in any legal action.

### 16\. Other Important Terms

16.1 We may transfer our rights and obligations under a Contract to another organisation, but this will not affect your rights or our obligations under these Conditions.

16.2 You may only transfer your rights or your obligations under these Conditions to another person if we agree in writing.

16.3 Subject to clause 2.9, this Contract is between you and us. No other person shall have any rights to enforce any of its terms.

16.4 Each of the paragraphs of these Conditions operates separately. If any court or relevant authority decides that any of them are unlawful or unenforceable, the remaining paragraphs will remain in full force and effect.

16.5 If we fail to insist that you perform any of your obligations under these Conditions, or if we do not enforce our rights against you, or if we delay in doing so, that will not mean that we have waived our rights against you and will not mean that you do not have to comply with those obligations. If we do waive a default by you, we will only do so in writing, and that will not mean that we will automatically waive any later default by you.

16.6 These Terms are governed by English law. This means a Contract for the purchase of Goods through our Website and any dispute or claim arising out of or in connection with it will be governed by English law. You and we both agree to that the courts of England and Wales will have non-exclusive jurisdiction. However, if you are a resident of Northern Ireland you may also bring proceedings in Northern Ireland, and if you are a resident of Scotland, you may also bring proceedings in Scotland.

Last Updated: 7 September 2017

Back to top

## Terms of Use

These terms set out how you may use our websites and our App. Please read these terms of use carefully, together with our Privacy Policy before you start to use any of our sites or our App. By using any of our sites or App you confirm that you accept these terms and that you agree to comply with them. If you do not agree to these terms of use, you must not use any of our sites.

### Access

We do not guarantee that any of our sites or our App, or any content on them, will always be available or be uninterrupted. We may suspend, withdraw, discontinue or change all or any part of our sites without notice. We will not be liable to you if for any reason one of our sites is unavailable at any time or for any period. We may limit the availability of our sites or any service or product described on any one of our sites to any person or geographic area at any time.

### No Reliance on Information

We have taken every care in the preparation of the content of our sites and our App. To the extent permitted by applicable law, we disclaim all warranties, express or implied, as to the accuracy of the information contained in any of the materials on any of our sites and our App. Due to the changing nature of the information contained on our sites and our App we shall have no liability whatsoever for any damages or losses arising directly or indirectly as a result of any of the information accessible via the sites and the App not being accurate, complete or up to date.

### Viruses

We do not guarantee that our sites or our App will be secure or free from bugs or viruses. Due to the nature and inherent risks of communications and the transfer of data over the internet, we shall have no liability whatsoever for any damages or losses resulting from viruses, worms, Trojan horses or other malicious code or the corruption or loss of data or any damage to software or hardware. You should use your own virus protection software.

You must not misuse any of our sites or our App by knowingly introducing viruses, Trojans, worms, logic bombs or other material which is malicious or technologically harmful. You must not attempt to gain unauthorised access to our sites our App, the server on which our sites or our App are stored or any server, computer or database connected to our sites or our App. You must not attack our sites or our App via a denial-of-service attack or a distributed denial-of service attack. By breaching this provision, you would commit a criminal offence under the Computer Misuse Act 1990 and we reserve the right to report any such breach to the relevant authorities.

### Registration

You warrant that the personal information which you are required to provide when you register as a user of one of our sites or our App is true, accurate, current and complete in all respects. You agree not to impersonate any other person or entity or to use a false name or a name that you are not authorised to use. You will notify us immediately of any changes to the personal information you have provided us with.

### Intellectual Property Rights

All copyright, trademarks and all other intellectual property rights in all material or content supplied as part of our sites or our App shall remain at all times vested in us or our licensors. You are permitted to use this material only as expressly authorised by us or our licensors.

You may download extracts of any page(s) from our sites or our App for your personal use or in accordance with any contractual relationship we have with you. However, you must not modify the paper or digital copies of any materials you have printed off or downloaded in any way, and you must not use any illustrations, photographs, video or audio sequences or any graphics separately from any accompanying text identifying the authors of content on our sites or our App.

### Social Media

These terms also govern any submissions you make on any third party website related to us or page such as any of our Facebook pages, Twitter, Pinterest, YouTube or social networking sites. All comments, images, videos and any other type of material posted on any third party social networking site do not necessarily reflect our opinions or ideas nor those of our employees and we are not responsible for any such content. In any event, all material posted on any third party social networking site must comply with these terms and the third party social networking sites' terms of use, as applicable.

Whenever you make use of a feature that allows you to upload content to our sites or our App, or to make contact with other users of our sites, you must comply with the acceptable standards set out in these terms.

### Acceptable Standards

Any and all material which you contribute to any of our sites or our App (" **contributions** "), and to any interactive services associated with them must comply with the following standards. Contributions must not:

  * Contain any material which is defamatory of any person or be threatening, abuse or invade another's privacy; or be likely to harass, upset, embarrass, alarm or annoy any other person.
  * Contain any material which is obscene, offensive, hateful or inflammatory including any sexually explicit material or promoting violence. 
  * Promote discrimination based on race, sex, religion, nationality, disability, sexual orientation or age.
  * Infringe any copyright, database right or trade mark of any other person.
  * Be made in breach of any legal duty owed to a third party, such as a contractual duty or a duty of confidence.
  * Promote any illegal activity.

You agree that you will only use our sites or our App for lawful purposes and will not:

  * Use them in any way that breaches any applicable local, national or international law or regulation.
  * Use them in any way that is unlawful or fraudulent, or has any unlawful or fraudulent purpose or effect.
  * Transmit, or procure the sending of, any unsolicited or unauthorised advertising or promotional material or any other form of similar solicitation (spam).
  * Knowingly transmit any data, send or upload any material that contains viruses, Trojan horses, worms, time-bombs, keystroke loggers, spyware, adware or any other harmful programs or similar computer code designed to adversely affect the operation of any computer software or hardware.
  * Reproduce, duplicate, copy or re-sell any part of our sites in contravention of the provisions these terms of use.

We will determine, in our discretion, whether there has been a breach of the above acceptable use requirements through your use of any of our sites or our App. When a breach of our requirements has occurred, we may take such action as we deem appropriate including immediate, temporary or permanent withdrawal of your right to use our site or our App and/or legal action.

### Interactive Services

We will do our best to assess any possible risks for users from third parties when they use any interactive service provided on our sites or our App, and we will decide in each case whether it is appropriate to use moderation of the relevant service (including what kind of moderation to use) in the light of those risks. However, we are under no obligation to oversee, monitor or moderate any interactive service we provide on our sites or our App, and we expressly exclude our liability for any loss or damage arising from the use of any interactive service by a user in contravention of the above requirements, whether the service is moderated or not.

### Third Party Links

Certain links on our sites and our App will lead to websites which are not under our control. When you activate any of these you will leave our site/App and we will have no control over and will accept no responsibility or liability for the material on any website which is not under our control. We assume no responsibility for the content of websites linked on our site and our App. Such links should not be interpreted as endorsement by us of those linked websites. We will not be liable for any loss or damage that may arise from your use of them.

### Applicable Law

These terms of use are governed by English law and subject to the non-exclusive jurisdiction of England and Wales. Nothing in these terms of use excludes or limits our liability for death or personal injury arising from our negligence, or our fraud or fraudulent misrepresentation, or any other liability that cannot be excluded or limited by English law.

Thank you for visiting our site.

Back to top

## App Privacy Policy

### **1\. Introduction**

Halfords Group PLC ("Halfords") is the UK's leading retailer of car parts, car enhancement, camping and touring equipment and bicycles, and the UK's largest independent operator in garage servicing and auto repair.

As an essential part of our business, we collect and manage customer data. In doing so, we observe UK data protection legislation, and are committed to protecting and respecting your privacy and rights.

In order that you are reliably informed about how we operate, we have developed this Privacy Statement. Together with any additional Privacy Notices which you may see as you navigate around this App, this Privacy Statement describes the ways in which we collect, manage, process, store and share information about you as a result of you using this App. 

This Privacy Statement also provides you with information about how you can have control over our use of your data.

Please note that we will be updating this Privacy Statement on a regular basis in order to keep you fully up-to-date with our approach to data protection and privacy. If you have any comments or queries regarding our use of your data, or you wish to unsubscribe from receiving marketing communications from us, please contact our Data Protection Officer ("DPO") by email at: [ dataprotectionofficer@halfords.co.uk](mailto:%20dataprotectionofficer@halfords.co.uk) or by post at: **Data Protection Officer, Icknield Street Drive, Washford West, Redditch, B98 0DE.**

### **2\. What Information Do We Collect About You**

The information that we collect about you may include your name, home address, date of birth, e-mail address, telephone number, as well as relevant financial and credit card information. This is referred to as your "personal data". We collect this data in a number of different ways. For example, you may provide this data directly when filling in forms on this App, or when corresponding with us by telephone, e-mail or letter.

Equally, when you use this App and even if you do not register with us, we may collect technical information about you such as your Internet Protocol (IP) address which connects your computer or mobile device to the internet, your login information, browser type and version, the country and telephone code where your computer is located, and information about your visit including products you viewed or searched for, page response times, download errors and length of visits to certain pages.

Only in very rare instances will we need to collect any sensitive information about you (known as "special categories of data") which includes, for example, details about your racial or ethnic origin, or data relating to your health. Should it ever be necessary for us to ask you for this type of data, we will provide you with separate details about how we will protect that information at that time.

### **3\. How Will We Use That Information?**

Currently, we use your data for the following purposes:

  * **3.1** To assist in the processing of your order / to carry out our obligations arising from any contracts entered into between you and us. For example, this could include packing and delivering orders, forwarding order details, order fulfilment, the processing of credit/debit card transactions, fraud prevention, registering warranties and the provision of corresponding customer services

In certain circumstances, it may be necessary for us to provide your information to external companies with which we contract to assist us in providing these critical services to you. We assure you that these companies are not permitted to use your information for any other purpose. For further information about these companies, please see section 5 below.

  * **3.2** Where you have given us your specific consent, we will use your data to provide you with marketing services. This allows us to tell you about new products or services that may be of interest to you. Again, we do use a number of external companies to help us provide such marketing services. However, these companies are prohibited from sharing your data with any other company. This means that by consenting to receive marketing from us, you will not receive marketing communications from anyone else.
  * **3.3** To ensure that the information contained within this App is presented in the most effective manner for you and for your computer or mobile device. This information allows us to update and improve the contents of our App, and ensure the smooth operation of internal processes, such as troubleshooting, data analysis, testing, research, statistical and survey purposes, and to keep our App as safe and secure as possible. For further information, please refer to our Cookies Policy, which can be found [here.](http://www.halfords.com/advice/customer-services/policies-regulations?topCategoryId=292503#tab_cookiepolicy)
  * **3.4** To understand what sections of the App you are visiting, so that we can subsequently contact you regarding particular products and services which may also be of interest. This facility is enabled by cookies, described in our Cookies Policy which can be found [here.](http://www.halfords.com/advice/customer-services/policies-regulations?topCategoryId=292503#tab_cookiepolicy) We do this as we think it is important to understand your shopping and browsing habits so that we can keep improving our service for you. 
  * **3.5** To share with other companies within our Group, where we believe there may be additional benefit for you. However, before we send you any marketing from these other Group companies, we will always first seek your explicit consent. A full list of the companies within our Group is available at [www.halfordscompany.com](http://www.halfordscompany.com/)

If you change your mind at any stage about receiving marketing from us, or if you do not want us to process your personal data for one or more of the reasons set out above, please contact our DPO as described in section 1 above. 

### **4\. How Long Will We Keep Your Data?**

Unless you ask us to do so, we will never keep your data for longer than is necessary for us to complete the activity for which your data was collected in the first place. However, sometimes there is a legitimate and/or legal reason that means we need to retain your data. In the coming months, we will add further detail to this Privacy Statement, setting out further information about our practices. 

### **5\. With Whom Do We Share Your Personal Data?**

We work with a number of external suppliers who support our business. This includes organisations which are critical to fulfilling customer orders as detailed in section 3.1 above, as well as those that help us with marketing, as detailed in section 3.2 above. In the coming months, this Statement will be updated to give further detail about the categories of suppliers that we use, specifically where these organisations are based outside the European Economic Area ("EEA"). We will also provide details about the security arrangements which are in place in order to protect customers' data. 

Notwithstanding the above, we assure you that we will only exchange your data with another organisation where i) we have your express permission to do so; or ii) it is necessary in order to honour a contract between you and Halfords; or (iii) we have a legal obligation to share the information; or (iv) it is in the public interest; or (v) it is necessary for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims; or (vi) it is necessary to protect the vital interests of you or another person.

We will never sell your personal data to any external organisation.

### **6\. How Can You Access The Personal Data We Hold?**

You have the right to ask us, in writing, for a copy of all the personal data we hold about you. This is known as a "Subject Access Request". Except in exceptional circumstances (which we would discuss and agree with you in advance), you can obtain this information at no cost. 

We will send you a copy of the information within 30 days of your request.

To make a Subject Access Request, please write to our DPO at the postal address shown in section 1 above. 

### **7\. Updating or Amending Your Personal Data**

If, at any time, you want to update or amend your personal data or consent preferences, please contact our DPO as described in section 1 above. Any requested and legitimate changes will take effect within 28 days of receipt of your request.

### **8\. Data Privacy and Security**

We maintain a comprehensive data management work programme, which includes processes for ensuring that data protection is a key consideration of all new and existing IT systems that hold customers' personal data. Where any concerns, risks or issues are identified, we conduct relevant impact assessments in order to determine any actions that are necessary to ensure optimum privacy.

We also maintain an active information security work programme which seeks to protect the availability, confidentiality and integrity of all physical and information assets. Specifically, this programme helps us to:

  * protect against potential breaches of confidentiality;
  * ensure all IT facilities are protected against damage, loss or misuse; and
  * increase awareness and understanding across our business of the requirements of information security, and the responsibility of colleagues to protect the confidentiality and integrity of the information that they handle.

We recognise that the security of data and transactions on this App is of primary importance. We therefore ensure that all connections to secure parts of the website (such as your personal account and the checkout section) are encrypted and authenticated using strong protocols, key exchanges and ciphers.

### **9\. Location Tracking Via Our Website**

This App only uses geo-location tracking, which shows us where you are in the UK, for specific situations. These include:.

  * **click and collect:** on the product pages, you can check the availability of any selected item in your local store;
  * **store locator:** you can search for your local store using your current location In both situations, your permission will be sought before geo-tracking is used, and then, it is only used to personalise your experience.

### **10\. Card Payment Security**

We are proud to have been awarded the Payment Card Industry Data Security Standard (PCI-DSS), which recognises the robust processes that we apply when handling card transactions from the major card schemes. This independent certification gives our customers assurance that our transactional systems protect your data with appropriate levels of security.

### **11\. Disclaimers**

Every effort is made to ensure that the information provided on this website, and in this Privacy Statement, is accurate and up-to-date, but no legal responsibility is accepted for any errors or omissions contained herein. 

We cannot accept liability for the use made by you of the information on this App or in this Privacy Statement, neither do we warrant that the supply of the information will be uninterrupted. All material accessed or downloaded from this App is obtained at your own risk. It is your responsibility to use appropriate anti-virus software. 

This Privacy Statement applies solely to the data collected by us, and therefore does not also apply to data collected by third party websites and services that are not under our control. Furthermore, we cannot be held responsible for the Privacy Statements on third party Apps or websites, and we advise users to read these carefully before registering any personal data. 

### **12\. Accessibility Statement**

We are committed to providing a website in which content is accessible to everyone. We therefore update our website regularly in order to make it as adaptable as possible. 

For example, website users can control the text size of each page within their internet browser. On a PC, holding the "Ctrl" key while pressing the "+" (plus) key will increase text size, and holding the "Ctrl" key while pressing the "-" (minus) key will decrease the text size. 

However, should you require a copy of this Privacy Statement in a different form, please contact our DPO as described in section 1 above. We cannot guarantee that we can fulfil all requests, but we will endeavour to help you as much as practical.

### **13\. General**

The Data Controller of this website is Halfords Group PLC, Icknield Street Drive, Washford West, Redditch, Worcestershire B98 0DE. 

Questions, comments and requests regarding this Privacy Statement are welcomed, and should be sent to our DPO.

Back to top

## Privacy Policy

### 1\. Introduction

Halfords Group PLC ("Halfords") is the UK's leading retailer of car parts, car enhancement, camping and touring equipment and bicycles, and the UK's largest independent operator in garage servicing and auto repair.

As an essential part of our business, we collect and manage customer data. In doing so, we observe UK data protection legislation, and are committed to protecting and respecting your privacy and rights.

In order that you are reliably informed about how we operate, we have developed this Privacy Statement. Together with any additional Privacy Notices which you may see as you navigate around this website, this Privacy Statement describes the ways in which we collect, manage, process, store and share information about you as a result of you visiting this site.

This Privacy Statement also provides you with information about how you can have control over our use of your data.

Please note that we will be updating this Privacy Statement on a regular basis in order to keep you fully up-to-date with our approach to data protection and privacy. If you have any comments or queries regarding our use of your data, or you wish to unsubscribe from receiving marketing communications from us, please contact our Data Protection Officer ("DPO") by email at: [ dataprotectionofficer@halfords.co.uk](mailto:%20dataprotectionofficer@halfords.co.uk) or by post at: **Data Protection Officer, Icknield Street Drive, Washford West, Redditch, B98 0DE.**

### 2\. What Information Do We Collect About You

The information that we collect about you may include your name, home address, date of birth, e-mail address, telephone number, as well as relevant financial and credit card information. This is referred to as your "personal data". We collect this data in a number of different ways. For example, you may provide this data directly when filling in forms on this website, or when corresponding with us by telephone, e-mail or letter.

Equally, when you visit this website and even if you do not register with us, we may collect technical information about you such as your Internet Protocol (IP) address which connects your computer or mobile device to the internet, your login information, browser type and version, the country and telephone code where your computer is located, and information about your visit including products you viewed or searched for, page response times, download errors and length of visits to certain pages.

Only in very rare instances will we need to collect any sensitive information about you (known as "special categories of data") which includes, for example, details about your racial or ethnic origin, or data relating to your health. Should it ever be necessary for us to ask you for this type of data, we will provide you with separate details about how we will protect that information at that time.

### 3\. How Will We Use That Information?

Currently, we use your data for the following purposes:

  * **3.1** To assist in the processing of your order / to carry out our obligations arising from any contracts entered into between you and us. For example, this could include packing and delivering orders, forwarding order details, order fulfilment, the processing of credit/debit card transactions, fraud prevention, registering warranties and the provision of corresponding customer services

In certain circumstances, it may be necessary for us to provide your information to external companies with which we contract to assist us in providing these critical services to you. We assure you that these companies are not permitted to use your information for any other purpose. For further information about these companies, please see section 5 below.

  * **3.2** Where you have given us your specific consent, we will use your data to provide you with marketing services. This allows us to tell you about new products or services that may be of interest to you. Again, we do use a number of external companies to help us provide such marketing services. However, these companies are prohibited from sharing your data with any other company. This means that by consenting to receive marketing from us, you will not receive marketing communications from anyone else.

  * **3.3** To ensure that the information contained within this website is presented in the most effective manner for you and for your computer or mobile device. This information allows us to update and improve the contents of our site, and ensure the smooth operation of internal processes, such as troubleshooting, data analysis, testing, research, statistical and survey purposes, and to keep our website as safe and secure as possible. For further information, please refer to our Cookies Policy, which can be found [here.](http://www.halfords.com/advice/customer-services/policies-regulations?topCategoryId=292503#tab_cookiepolicy)

  * **3.4** To understand what sections of the website you are visiting, so that we can subsequently contact you regarding particular products and services which may also be of interest. This facility is enabled by cookies, described in our Cookies Policy which can be found [here.](http://www.halfords.com/advice/customer-services/policies-regulations?topCategoryId=292503#tab_cookiepolicy) We do this as we think it is important to understand your shopping and browsing habits so that we can keep improving our service for you. 

  * **3.5** To share with other companies within our Group, where we believe there may be additional benefit for you. However, before we send you any marketing from these other Group companies, we will always first seek your explicit consent. A full list of the companies within our Group is available at [www.halfordscompany.com](http://www.halfordscompany.com/)

If you change your mind at any stage about receiving marketing from us, or if you do not want us to process your personal data for one or more of the reasons set out above, please contact our DPO as described in section 1 above.

### 4\. How Long Will We Keep Your Data?

Unless you ask us to do so, we will never keep your data for longer than is necessary for us to complete the activity for which your data was collected in the first place. However, sometimes there is a legitimate and/or legal reason that means we need to retain your data. In the coming months, we will add further detail to this Privacy Statement, setting out further information about our practices. 

### 5\. With Whom Do We Share Your Personal Data?

We work with a number of external suppliers who support our business. This includes organisations which are critical to fulfilling customer orders as detailed in section 3.1 above, as well as those that help us with marketing, as detailed in section 3.2 above. In the coming months, this Statement will be updated to give further detail about the categories of suppliers that we use, specifically where these organisations are based outside the European Economic Area ("EEA"). We will also provide details about the security arrangements which are in place in order to protect customers? data. 

Notwithstanding the above, we assure you that we will only exchange your data with another organisation where i) we have your express permission to do so; or ii) it is necessary in order to honour a contract between you and Halfords; or (iii) we have a legal obligation to share the information; or (iv) it is in the public interest; or (v) it is necessary for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims; or (vi) it is necessary to protect the vital interests of you or another person.

We will never sell your personal data to any external organisation.

### 6\. How Can You Access The Personal Data We Hold? 

You have the right to ask us, in writing, for a copy of all the personal data we hold about you. This is known as a "Subject Access Request". Except in exceptional circumstances (which we would discuss and agree with you in advance), you can obtain this information at no cost. 

We will send you a copy of the information within 30 days of your request.

To make a Subject Access Request, please write to our DPO at the postal address shown in section 1 above. 

### 7\. Updating or Amending Your Personal Data 

If, at any time, you want to update or amend your personal data or consent preferences, please contact our DPO as described in section 1 above. Any requested and legitimate changes will take effect within 28 days of receipt of your request.

### 8\. Data Privacy and Security

We maintain a comprehensive data management work programme, which includes processes for ensuring that data protection is a key consideration of all new and existing IT systems that hold customers? personal data. Where any concerns, risks or issues are identified, we conduct relevant impact assessments in order to determine any actions that are necessary to ensure optimum privacy.

We also maintain an active information security work programme which seeks to protect the availability, confidentiality and integrity of all physical and information assets. Specifically, this programme helps us to:

  * protect against potential breaches of confidentiality;
  * ensure all IT facilities are protected against damage, loss or misuse; and
  * increase awareness and understanding across our business of the requirements of information security, and the responsibility of colleagues to protect the confidentiality and integrity of the information that they handle.

We recognise that the security of data and transactions on this website is of primary importance. We therefore ensure that all connections to secure parts of the website (such as your personal account and the checkout section) are encrypted and authenticated using strong protocols, key exchanges and ciphers.

### 9\. Location Tracking Via Our Website

This website only uses geo-location tracking, which shows us where you are in the UK, for specific situations. These include:.

  * **click and collect:** on the product pages, you can check the availability of any selected item in your local store;
  * **store locator:** you can search for your local store using your current location In both situations, your permission will be sought before geo-tracking is used, and then, it is only used to personalise your experience.

### 10\. Card Payment Security

We are proud to have been awarded the Payment Card Industry Data Security Standard (PCI-DSS), which recognises the robust processes that we apply when handling card transactions from the major card schemes. This independent certification gives our customers assurance that our transactional systems protect your data with appropriate levels of security.

### 11\. Disclaimers

Every effort is made to ensure that the information provided on this website, and in this Privacy Statement, is accurate and up-to-date, but no legal responsibility is accepted for any errors or omissions contained herein. 

We cannot accept liability for the use made by you of the information on this website or in this Privacy Statement, neither do we warrant that the supply of the information will be uninterrupted. All material accessed or downloaded from this website is obtained at your own risk. It is your responsibility to use appropriate anti-virus software. 

This Privacy Statement applies solely to the data collected by us, and therefore does not also apply to data collected by third party websites and services that are not under our control. Furthermore, we cannot be held responsible for the Privacy Statements on third party websites, and we advise users to read these carefully before registering any personal data. 

### 12\. Accessibility Statement 

We are committed to providing a website in which content is accessible to everyone. We therefore update our website regularly in order to make it as adaptable as possible. 

For example, website users can control the text size of each page within their internet browser. On a PC, holding the ?Ctrl? key while pressing the ?+? (plus) key will increase text size, and holding the ?Ctrl? key while pressing the "-" (minus) key will decrease the text size. 

However, should you require a copy of this Privacy Statement in a different form, please contact our DPO as described in section 1 above. We cannot guarantee that we can fulfil all requests, but we will endeavour to help you as much as practical.

### 13\. General

The Data Controller of this website is Halfords Group PLC, Icknield Street Drive, Washford West, Redditch, Worcestershire B98 0DE. 

Questions, comments and requests regarding this Privacy Statement are welcomed, and should be sent to our DPO.

Back to top

Back to top

## Olapic Terms and Conditions

## Cookie Policy

### What are Cookies?

A cookie is a very small text file that can be stored on your computer when you visit a web page. Cookies are used to help you navigate the website and to enhance your experience whilst on the website. Cookies enable a website to tailor information presented to you based on your browsing preferences.

### Why do Halfords use Cookies?

Halfords use cookies to collect data about the performance of our websites and to ensure an easy and consistent user experience for our visitors.

Halfords may use cookies to personalise web pages during your visit to our websites. We will also use them to remember you for easy navigation and access during your visit. For example, when you use the stock checker, we will remember your postcode for the duration of your visit **only** to save you having to re-enter your postcode each time you want to check stock in your local store.

We may also use cookies to track your visit to our websites and to help us create a profile of your preferences and interests. We will collect data to identify you whilst you are browsing so that we can measure our websites, make improvements in the future and respect your marketing preferences.

**Can cookies harm my computer?**

No. Cookies do not harm your computer and cannot carry viruses. Cookies are intended to enhance your experience of a website, rather than obstruct it.

More Information About Cookies

To learn more about cookies, how to manage them and how they affect your online activities, visit [www.aboutcookies.org](http://www.aboutcookies.org/ "About cookies").

### Managing Cookies

Halfords use cookies on our all of our websites to improve your shopping experience. These cookies can make it quicker and easier to browse and navigate our websites in just some of the following ways:

  * They remember items that you have added to your basket so you can buy them later on in your visit
  * They allow you to compare products whilst shopping
  * They can remember your previous selections when you are browsing the website
  * When you use the stock checker, the website will remember your postcode **for the duration of your visit only** to save you re-entering your postcode each time you want to check stock in your local store

In general, allowing cookies lets you make the most of all the functionalities on our websites, which have been added to give you the best possible shopping experience.

If you would still prefer Halfords **not** to use cookies in your browser, you can set your browser to reject cookies or to let you know when a website tries to put one in your browser software.

**How to Disable Cookies**

On Your PC

**Internet Explorer**

  1. Go to "Tools" and then "Internet Options"
  2. Click on the Privacy tab
  3. Use the slider to change your cookie settings to how you want them. A description of each setting will appear next to each option.

**Mozilla Firefox**

  1. Go to "Tools" and then "Internet Options"
  2. Click on the Privacy icon
  3. Change the history settings to set your browser to reject all cookies, or to tailor your cookie settings to how you want them.

**Google Chrome**

  1. Click on the spanner and select "Settings", which will open in a new tab
  2. On the left hand side, select "Under the Hood"
  3. Click "Content Settings" under "Privacy"
  4. Choose your preferred option in the cookies menu

On an Apple Mac

**Internet Explorer 5 (MacOS X)**

  1. Choose Preferences from Explorer menu
  2. Select Receiving Files options
  3. Select Cookies
  4. Choose your preferred settings

**Mozilla**

  1. Choose Preferences from the Edit menu.
  2. Select Privacy & Security, then select Cookies.
  3. Choose your preferred settings.

**Safari 1.0 (MacOS X)**

  1. Choose Preferences from Safari menu
  2. Select Security icon
  3. Cookie settings are shown in window
  4. Choose your preferred settings

**Opera**

  1. Go to Opera in the main menu and select Preferences (or press Alt+P to access them directly)
  2. Select Privacy

Mobile

**iPad**

  1. Go to "Settings" and then select "Safari"
  2. Click on "Privacy", where you will be able to change your cookie settings

**iPhone**

  1. Go to "Settings" and then select "Safari"
  2. Click on "Privacy", where you will be able to change your cookie settings

**Samsung Galaxy**

  1. In the internet browser, open the menu and select "More"
  2. Choose "Settings"
  3. Scroll down to "Privacy", and then click to accept or reject cookies, or to clear cookie data

All Other Mobile Devices

All Other Mobile Devices Please consult the device owner's manual.

### Halfords Cookies

For the best experience on any Halfords website, your PC, laptop, mobile or tablet will need to accept cookies. Without cookies, you will not be able to make a purchase, or benefit from certain personalised features.

So that you know exactly what cookies are used on our websites, we have listed each cookie below, along with its purpose.

Third party cookies used on our websites are listed in the next tab.

If you still wish to block or delete cookies from any of our sites, the "Managing Cookies" tab will be able to help.

**Cookie Name**

**Description**

**H_STOCK_CHECKER_10001**

This cookie is used by the stock checker and remembers your town or postcode for the next time you use it. Your town or postcode is only remembered for the duration of your visit.

**10001_VRN and H_VRN_10001**

We use this cookie to remember your car registration number when you enter it into our vehicle lookup tool to save you from having to re-enter details the next time you use it.

**Halca**

This cookie remembers any adverts that you have clicked on to arrive at the Halfords website. This is needed to make sure that our advertisers are paid their commission when a transaction is made.

**HalfordsCarSelectorCookie_10001**

When you are looking for vehicle specific parts, this cookie builds the list of relevant products according to each selection you make.

**MARKETUT**

This cookie remembers whether you are a registered user or not.

**H_COMPARISON_ / H_COMPARISON_10001**

This cookie allows the comparison function to remember the products you want to compare across multiple pages. You wouldn't be able to compare our products without it.

**Websphere Cookies**

Halfords websites have been developed using IBM Websphere Commerce software. This software employs a number of cookiesto enable Halfords customers to navigate and shop on all of the websites. All these cookies are essential to ensuring a pleasant and easy customer shopping experience. None of the cookies hold Personally Identifiable Information. These cookies are described in more detail below:

**Cookie Name**

**Description**

**WC_ACTIVEPOINTER**

This cookie remembers whether you are on the halfords.com or halfords.ie site

**WC_AUTHENTICATION**

This cookie is used to authenticate the user over SSL connections to ensure that all personal information is totally secure and to confirm that you are the person you claim to be in the checkout.

**WC_GENERIC_ACTIVITYDATA**

When you navigate the website, our system requires you to be a registered customer, a guest customer or a "generic" customer. This cookies assigns a generic user id to anyone who enters the website via any page other than the homepage (where you are assigned either guest user id or registered user id if signed in).

**WC_MEMBERID**

This cookie holds an internal id for everyone who is either a guest user or a registered user. This information is used for navigating the website.

**WC_PERSISTENT**

This cookie holds information about a user to ensure the correct version of the website is being displayed for the user, i.e. the language (English). This cookie also stores your preferences (language, currency etc) to enable easy navigation of website.

**WC_USERACTIVITY**

This cookie holds user session information to ensure effective navigation between the web browser and the web server, for example going back and forward on web pages. This cookie does not hold any Personally Identifiable Information.

**Apache  
HalfordsReturnToCatalog   
H_RETURN_10001   
LtpaToken2   
WC_USERSESSION_1002   
WC_USERSESSION-23669148   
WC_USERSESSION_ESTABLISHED   
WC_ACTIVESTOREDATA**

These cookies are used to back IBM Websphere, the basis of our website. They ensure the effective running of our site and do not hold any Personally Identifiable Information.

Coremetrics Cookies

Halfords websites use Coremetrics analytic software provided by our business partner, IBM. Coremetrics software helps us to measure the performance of our site and to make future improvements based on customer activity. Coremetrics employs a number of cookies to enable this. **None** of these cookies (listed below) hold Personally Identifiable Information :

**Cookie Name**

**Description**

**_AN_CGCEMAP_COOKIE  
CM_CATEGORY_MAP_COOKIE   
CM_COOKIE   
cmRS   
cmTPSet   
CoreAt   
CoreID6   
CoreM_State   
90208059_clogin   
99999999_clogin **

These cookies enable the function of our analytics software, Coremetrics. This software helps us to measure the performance of our websites and analyse information such as visitor numbers, visit lengths, page views and the devices used to browse our websites. We use this data to track trends and improve our websites.

**Flash Cookies (Local Shared Objects)**

Halfords use Adobe Flash Player to deliver all video content on product pages and in the Advice Centre - for example the "How To" guides. To improve your experience, Flash Cookies (also known as Local Shared Objects) are stored on your computer in the same way as other cookies, but they are managed slightly differently, not through your browser.

**How to disable Flash Cookies:**

To disable or delete flash cookies, you will need to visit the [Adobe website.](http://www.adobe.com/security/flashplayer/ "Adobe website") Please be aware that if you disable flash cookies then you will not be able to access any flash based content such as video.

**Third Party Cookies**

Cookies on the Halfords site may also be set by one of our partners who set cookies for a number of different reasons. These third parties are listed below with a description of the cookies set by them

Halfords do not control these cookies. To change your settings for these cookies, click on the relevant link, which will take you to the third party site where you will be able to manage the cookies.

**Cookie Name**

**Description**

**Affiliate Window**

Affiliate Window cookies track the activity of affiliates and reward them for generating traffic and sales on our websites.   
Go to [Affiliate Window](http://www.affiliatewindow.com/documents/Privacy%20Policy.pdf "Affiliate window") for more information on managing Affiliate Window cookies.

**Bazaarvoice**

Halfords use Bazaarvoice for managing ratings & reviews and Ask & Answer functionality on all of the websites. As part of this a cookie is served on your machine.   
Go to [Bazaarvoice](http://www.bazaarvoice.com/consumer-privacy-policy "Bazaarvoice") for more information on managing Bazaarvoice cookies

**Bing**

Bing cookies originate in our PPC campaigns with Bing, rewarding them for generating traffic and sales on our website   
Go to [Bing](https://choice.microsoft.com/AdvertisementChoice/ "Bing") for more information on managing Bing cookies. 

**Criteo**

Criteo provides you with personalised adverts when you visit selected other websites by placing a Criteo cookie on yourcomputer. This cookie does not contain any personal data.   
Go to [Criteo](http://www.criteo.com/us/privacy-policy "Criteo") for more information on managing Criteo cookies. 

**DC Storm**

DC Storm cookies identify how users interact with the Halfords websites so that we can see things like the most popular pages and the journey that our customers take through the websites. This information is used to make future improvements to our websites. None of these cookies hold any Personally Identifiable Information.   
Go to [DC Storm](http://www.dc-storm.com/information-on-cookies/ "DC Storm") for more information on managing DC Storm cookies.

**DoubleClick**

Doubleclick cookies serve carefully selected ads on a users computer.   
Go to [DoubleClick](http://www.google.com/doubleclick/ "Double click") for more information on managing DoubleClick cookies.

**eDigital Research (eCustomerOpinions)**

To provide a better service, occasionally we may ask visitors to our website to complete a survey. eDigital Research cookies remember if we have asked you to take a survey recently to ensure we obtain a wide sample of visitors. The cookie contains no personal information and will expire after 6 months.  
Go to [eDigitalResearch](http://www.edigitalresearch.com/static/privacy) for more information on managing eDigitalResearch cookies.

**Google**

Google cookies originate in our PPC campaigns with Google, rewarding them for generating traffic and sales on our website   
Go to [Google](http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/ads/ "Google") for more information on managing Google cookies.

**Maxymiser**

Maxymiser cookies allow us to recognise and count the number of visitors to see how visitors browse around the site. This helps us to understand things that don't work well and to improve your experience of halfords.com. Maxymiser never shares data or observations with anyone outside of Halfords and the data is used at an aggregated level so it does not and is never used to identify you.   
Go to [Maxymiser](http://www.maxymiser.com/cookies "Maxymiser") for more information on managing Maxymiser cookies.

**TradeDoubler**

TradeDoubler cookies track the activity of affiliates and reward them for generating traffic and sales on our websites.   
Go to [TradeDoubler](http://hstse.tradedoubler.com/file/20649/uk/help_centre/faq_tracking.htm "Trade doubler") for more information on managing TradeDoubler cookies.

**Intelligent Reach (formally Ultimate Feed/Shop Submit)**

Intelligent Reach cookies track the activity of affiliates and reward them for generating traffic and sales on our websites.   
Go to [Intelligent Reach](http://www.intelligentreach.com/privacy-cookies/ "Intelligent Reach") for more information on managing Intelligent Reach cookies.

Back to top

## Chemical Regulations

Halfords supplies many chemical-based products online, via our catalogue and in-store. All retailers selling chemical products are obliged to comply with European directives by providing key health and safety information for this type of product. Several key European Directives/Regulations exist governing the supply of chemical products with regard to labelling, packaging and marketing and these regulations also require health and safety documentation to be made readily available.

The Regulations themselves are designed to protect both the environment and human health, and as a responsible supplier Halfords naturally takes its obligations very seriously and ensures it complies and enforces these regulations.

[Halfords Health and Safety information](http://www.my-sds.co.uk/default.asp?accountid=guest&languagecode=44&companyid=halfords) for chemical products provides access to the latest up-to-date label information, Safety Data Sheets and Detergent Ingredient Data sheets.

To access further information, follow the link above, then select ’Name’ for the search criteria in the left-hand drop-down box, and in the box underneath, enter either the full name of your product if know, e.g. Halfords 5W30 VW Fully Synthetic Oil, or a generic name, e.g. oil, click ’Search’, and all the products we have information on will be displayed in the box to the right. Then simply click on the rectangular symbol to display the safety data sheet, or the diamond symbol to display the chemical supply symbol. 

Should you have any queries regarding this or any other safety issues please contact our customer services department

Back to top

## Terms for free in-store WiFi

### Halfords WiFi

These are Halfords Limited's ( **Halfords** , **we** or **us** ) terms for the provision of wireless and broadband communication services which allow you to access the internet via our WiFi networks ( **our service** ) when you are either located within or close to any of the participating Halfords stores. You should understand that by using our service, you agree to be bound by these terms.

Please read these terms carefully. By choosing "Register" on your mobile phone you will choose to use our service. If you do not accept these terms, you will not be permitted to use our service.

### **Provision of the Service**

When using our service, you agree at all times to comply with our Terms of Use and our  Privacy Policy.

It is your responsibility to ensure that your mobile device is compatible with our service and is switched on. The availability and performance of our service is subject to all memory, storage and any other limitations in your mobile device. Our service is only available to your mobile device when it is within the operating range of participating Halfords stores. Our service is subject to non-availability, including non-availability due to emergencies, collocation failures, transmission and equipment limitations, or maintenance and repair, and may be interrupted, refused, limited or curtailed.

Halfords are not responsible for data, messages, or pages that you may lose or that become misdirected because of interruptions or performance issues with our service or wireless communications networks generally. Halfords may impose usage, or service limits, suspend service, or block certain kinds of usage in Halfords sole discretion, to protect other users of our service. Network speed is no indication of the speed at which your mobile device or our service sends or receives data. Actual network speed will vary based on configuration, compression and network congestion.

Halfords does not warrant or guarantee the performance of the internet or that the transmission of information over the internet will be secure or that the internet will be accessible at all times. You agree to use these services entirely at your own risk.

### Use of the Service

You may access our service in accordance with these terms for your own personal use. You agree not to resell any aspect of our service, whether for profit or otherwise, or to authorise any other third party to use our service. You agree not to use our service for any illegal, fraudulent, obscene, unlawful, harassing, or abusive purpose, including the sending of any unsolicited commercial text or email messages in such a way as to create damage or risk to Halfords' business, reputation, employees, subscribers, customers, facilities, or to the public generally. You agree not to intentionally transmit any computer viruses or do anything that is likely to interfere with the provision of our service.

Halfords are not responsible for any sites that you access whilst using our service, or any activities that you carry out on the internet (including any items which are downloaded from the internet). Halfords does not guarantee that products or services or any sites accessible via our service are error or virus free. All such activities are carried out at your own risk and it is your responsibility to ensure that you have the right to carry them out. Third party sites will have their own terms and conditions, terms of use and privacy policies which will apply if you access third party sites. Please check these terms and policies before you use any third party sites or carry out any activities in connection with them.

We have the right to suspend or terminate our service immediately in the event that you breach any of the provisions of these terms, our Terms of Use, or our Privacy Policy including without limitation:

  * if you use any equipment which is defective or illegal;
  * if you cause any technical or other problems to our service;
  * if, in our opinion, you are involved in fraudulent or unauthorised use of our service;
  * if you resell access to our service; or
  * if you use our service in contravention of the Terms of Use.

### Privacy and Data Protection

Privacy cannot be guaranteed and Halfords will not be liable to you for any lack of privacy that you experience while using our service.

We shall process all information about you which is provided in relation to our service in accordance with our Privacy Policy.

While we agree to take all necessary technical and organisational steps to ensure the security of our service, we are not responsible for the accidental loss or destruction of any personal data you transmit using our service and we exclude all liability of any kind in relation to the content or security of personal data that you send or receive through our service.

You agree and acknowledge that we may be required by law to provide assistance to law enforcement, governmental agencies and other authorities. Accordingly, you agree:

  * that we may implement and maintain an interception capability suitable to meet these requirements where we are obliged by law to ensure or procure that such a capability is implemented and maintained;
  * that we may implement and maintain a data retention capability for our service to meet requirements where we are obliged by law to ensure or procure that data is retained; and
  * we may at times co-operate with law enforcement authorities and rights-holders in the investigation of any suspected or alleged illegal activity by you. If we are required to do so by law, this may include but is not limited to, disclosure of your contact information to law enforcement authorities or rights-holders.

We will use your personal data for the purposes set out in our Privacy Policy. You acknowledge and accept that Halfords may use your personal data for marketing purposes to contact you (by post, email or SMS) about products and services which we feel may be of interest to you. If at any time you no longer wish to receive information from us, please email us at [customer.services@halfords.co.uk](mailto:customer.services@halfords.co.uk)

### Our Liability

Halfords' maximum aggregate liability to you for losses or damages suffered in respect of all claims arising in connection with these terms shall not exceed £500.

To the extent permitted by law, we, other members of our group of companies hereby expressly exclude:

  * all conditions, warranties and other terms which might otherwise be implied by statute, common law or the law of equity; and
  * any liability for any direct, indirect or consequential loss or damage incurred by you in connection with our service, including: loss of income or revenue; loss of business; loss of profits or contracts; loss of anticipated savings; loss of data; loss of goodwill and whether caused by tort (including negligence), breach of contract or otherwise, even if foreseeable, provided that this condition shall not prevent claims for loss of or damage to your tangible property or any other claims for direct financial loss that are not excluded by any of the categories set out above.

This does not affect our liability for death or personal injury arising from our negligence, nor our liability for fraudulent misrepresentation or misrepresentation as to a fundamental matter, nor any other liability which cannot be excluded or limited under applicable law.

### General

We will not be liable or responsible for any failure to perform, or delay in performance of, any of our obligations under these terms that is caused by events outside our reasonable control ( **Force Majeure Event** ).

These terms and any dispute or claim arising out of or in connection with them or their subject matter or formation (including non-contractual disputes or claims) shall be governed by and construed in accordance with the law of England and Wales and the courts of England and Wales shall have exclusive jurisdiction to settle any dispute or claim that arises out of or in connection with these terms.

Back to top
